ROWAN GAGNON

Software Developer

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Recent Software Engineering graduate with experience in back-end web development and a strong interest in software design and video game development.

Highly sociable and adaptable within teams, seeking to expand skillset in software development earned throughout two years of professional internships.

CONTACT

- 514-664-5628
- xrgagnon@gmail.com
- (in) linkedin.com/in/rowangagnon/

KEY SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C++, C#, Javascript, Python, PHP
- **Tools:** Git, Unity game engine, Docker, Axure, SQL, Blender
- Frameworks: VueJS, Hugo, Laravel, scikit-learn

- Highly cooperative
- · Very fast learner
- Adaptive, autonomous
- · Highly sociable
- Fluent in French/English

EDUCATION

B. Eng. Software Engineering (2019-2024)

École de Technologie Supérieure

Relevant Modules: Software design patterns, Artificial Intelligence algorithms, UI design, Game programming and design, Graphics programming

WORK EXPERIENCE

Trisotech, Laval

Software Engineering Intern, September 2023 - December 2023

- Migrated business websites from Wordpress to the Hugo framework.
- Optimized the response time of dynamic content pages.
- Refactored a javascript code base using VueJS to reduce maintenance effort costs.

eSimpleIT, Montreal

Web Developer, January 2021 – March 2023

- Designed and implemented a scalable infrastructure for a data transformation automation tool.
- Integrated a CRN REST API into a web data automation tool.
- Optimized a database update/migration process.

Skytech Communications, Montreal

Analyst Programmer , March 2022 – August 2022

- Implemented data visualization features for a complex .NET web application.
- Designed and refactored large T-SQL queries and tables.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

- Reservist Infantry Soldier, Canadian Armed Forces (2017-2019)
- Intern Developer, Intact Assurances (2020)
- Unity Game Engine teacher, StudioXP (2020-2021)